Looking for better results from your sponsored brands campaigns?
Here's a guided breakdown
to help you learn how to refine your targeting, increase relevant impressions, and ultimately
drive more clicks.
By the end, you'll understand how to connect each stage of your
campaign to better performance and feel confident optimizing for real business results.
Refine targeting to help grow relevant impressions.
Start by reviewing keyword reports in the
advertising console.
Focus on keywords that have driven at least five orders while maintaining
a healthy ROAS.
For those that are new to sponsored brands or not seeing conversions yet,
use the Search Query Performance Report in Seller Central to identify keywords customers
used to find products like yours.
Choose keywords with higher search query scores to
increase chances of conversion and don't forget to align them with a strong bidding strategy.
Use higher bids for exact match keywords with high conversion potential.
Set moderate bids for
phrase match, especially branded terms.
Apply lower bids for broad match to manage spend while
expanding reach.
Reference Amazon suggested bid ranges when setting bids, and remember low
impressions might mean that bids are too low or targeting is too narrow.
Continuously adjust
based on performance data, for example, by shifting budget from underperforming to high performing
keywords.
Use product targeting to reach customers, browsing similar items, even from other brands.
To keep impressions relevant and impactful, include products where offers add strong values
such as those with lower star ratings, fewer reviews, not eligible for prime shipping,
and higher price points.
Exclude products priced too above or below your range for better efficiency.
Combine keyword and product targeting strategies to improve reach and relevance.
For better results, we recommend using both in tandem.
Additionally,
prevent unwanted impressions by creating a negative list of specific brands, products,
or high-cost keywords that aren't driving performance.
This helps ensure your ads don't appear on
product detail pages or search results that are unlikely to convert, helping maintain efficiency
while reaching the most relevant audiences.
Improve click-through rate.
The next move is turning
views into clicks by aligning targeting, creative, and landing page experience for a fluid shopping
journey.
First, align keywords with the ASINs featured in your ad and the landing page experience.
For a simpler approach, consider using theme targeting to help streamline this alignment.
Next, feature creatives that connect and test variations to find out which has more impact.
Video or imagery?
Dive into those learnings for future iterations of your ads.
Finally, consider campaign goals and build tailored brand store sub pages that showcase
different product collections or structure your home page for products or categories.
This can help capture additional ad traffic and open up cross-marketing opportunities.
In both cases, ensure the products featured in your ads appear prominently on the page and
include interactive elements like shoppable images.
Be sure to check metrics that signal
business growth potential like top-of-search impression share to identify opportunities
for increased visibility and brand searches and detail page views in brand metrics to assess how
ads are supporting brand recognition and driving shoppers to search a product or brand by name.
Allow at least 14 days for campaigns to gather insights before making major changes.
This is especially important when preparing for high traffic events like Prime Day,
where historical trends can help inform strategy.
Visit the ad console and start optimizing your
campaigns.